

# **Tsvetan** Tsvetanov Web Developer











tsvetan.tsvetanov.tsvetanov@gmail.com

+359884535237

s badnineteen

## **MOTIVATION**

Your positions seems like a good match to me because I'm interested in expanding my knowledge and experience in web crawling, digital marketing/SEO.

I have years of proven experience as a backend developer and basic experience with web crawling.

Ever since university I've been interested in regular languages and grammars and what we can or cannot do with them.

#### **EDUCATION**

Oct 2016 - Ongoing

Faculty of Mathematics and Informatics, Plovdiv University

Master in Software Tehcnologies

Oct 2008 - Sep 2015

Faculty of Mathematics and Informatics, Sofia University

Bachelor of Software Engineering

Sep 2003 - May 2008

High School of Natural Sciences and Mathematics, Sliven

Mathematics and English Language

## **EXPERIENCE**

January 2018 - February 2018

Starcoders

PHP Developer

Sofia, Bulgaria/Remote

- Worked on a stack of interconnected web apps providing high-load end user
- Slack, screen sharing, pair programming
- Agile process backlog refining, demo meetups, slack instead of daily standups
- International team.

August 2017 - September 2017

Vedesoft

Backend developer

Remote

- Worked on a web app backend
- Developed JSON API with PHP/MySQL
- Office was Jira and Slack

December 2016 - August 2017

Cloud Faces

Web developer with PHP

Sofia, Bulgaria

- Worked on the web component of factory for mobile apps
- Mostly backend, but occasionally did frontend tasks as well.
- Support & development of REST API (Epiphany, Lumen).
- Laravel "frontend" to call the APIs.
- Dev environment configuration (LAMP stack).

October 2016 - December

2016

Webstep
Web developer

Remote

- Worked on a web-based application (internal company project)
- Full-stack Laravel: Eloquent, Blade, jQuery, AJAX
- Skype/voice communication

August 2015 - June 2016

Programista / SevOne

Web developer Plovdiv, Bulgaria

- Worked for outstaffing company (Programista) and was dedicated a big client (SevOne) for 6 months
- Supported a multi-language (in both meanings) Network monitoring system, running o Linux-based virtual machines
- The 'front-end' application was written in PHP, MySQL, ExtJS
- Scrum training (workshop) by Michael James Scrum
- Internal training in Laravel

March 2014 - March 2015

Opencode Systems

Service Creation Engineer

Sofia, Bulgaria

- Together with team created core services for mobile operators worldwide
- Vanilla Javascript, MySQL, PHP, XML
- Waterfall process, overtime on demand
- Created Visio diagrams and other documentation

July 2011 - December 2013

Gameloft
Web developer

Sofia, Bulgaria

- Worked in E-commerce team
- Development and bug-fixing of WAP shops
- Sales monitoring and troubleshooting problems
- PHP, MySQL, xHTML

#### **SKILLS**

OS	<ul><li>Linux</li><li>Android</li></ul>	<ul><li>Windows</li></ul>	<ul><li>MacOS</li></ul>
Computer Languages	<ul><li>PHP</li><li>Bash</li><li>XML</li></ul>	<ul><li>MySQL</li><li>Python</li></ul>	• jQuery • (x)HTML
Version Control	GIT CLI Bitbucket	<ul><li>Gitlab</li><li>SVN</li></ul>	<ul><li>Github</li></ul>

PM TOOLS

JIRATrelloRedmineTask Freak

Mantis

